this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
softball this episode of SC radio is
brought to you by Braintree if you think
that your payment system exists solely
for the purpose of transferring money
from your customers wallet to yours
think again Braintree rethink payments
learn more at Braintree payment's calm
/se radio so welcome everyone to the
software engineering radio today
I'm your host Kim Carter and today we've
got gist francois Reynard Francoise way
note is the founder of DIF sitcom
conference I rent a training it recently
he's actively involved in security
automation projects supporting
continuous delivery and currently
working as the enterprise security
architect for a global retailer preceded
by 17 years at ASOS a bit far Verizon
Business HSBC in RSA where his
consulting engagement spanned across
implementing cert teams Incident
Response strategy security architecture
design IT security management and
penetration testing
welcome to the show Francois thank you
very much Kim really pleased to be here
so we've had quite a few shows on DevOps
before one of which was Andrew Phillips
an episode number 247 there was also
episode 221 with Gia's humble on
continuous delivery both of which are
good primers for what we're about to
discuss today I will also link to these
in the show notes
so DC cops is a topic that's close to my
heart you know I've been a practicing
preaching and training on for quite a
long time I just never realized that I
was formalized with a name until
recently
can you francois give us a quick summary
of what DevOps is in here the seek part
fits in' what is DC cops
and what does it look like so depth
AQAP's is really about finally
implementing security into DevOps and
traditional development processes it's
the ability to make sure that security
is going to be at the forefront of any
requirements thus avoiding those costly
mistake that we all do and restless
thinking about security after NAFTA so
one way to think about there sec ops is
traditional security has always been
about exclusion need-to-know using the
security policy to bash people around
the head not to come close to your to
our trade secrets and what we're trying
to do in deficit cops is really
promoting inclusion working as a team
and ensuring that we all seeing the same
in shape and it's a it's a team effort
basically so it's using all that DevOps
methodology as in the iterative
processes for our own benefits and
teaching everybody about security one
way to look at it is you just want to
break all the silos of security you just
want to give the knowledge tools of
different teams and ensuring that
security is actually thought about and
implemented at the right level and at
the right time in order to have people
embrace an idea in culture like deep sea
cops we need to discuss what is
defective with the status quo way of
creating and delivering technical
solutions can you explain for our
listeners what's wrong with our
traditional delivery approaches and
maybe including some examples of project
failures that may not have failed if
they took a more Deva Katta proach in
which specific dev see cops practices
would have saved the project okay so
traditional delivery methodology it's
really involving getting code from each
of the teams and just merging them
together into a final build
and at the end usually you've got a
project manager which is arriving to
security team and saying hey guys I
completely forgot I've got this line
item somewhere which is saying get
security approval so as a security
security team there was we've confronted
with the fact of we've got to release
this product to the market we've got to
make some money for the company can
please sign up and then you start
digging into the application the network
and you realize that no security has
been implemented so you end up basically
after the QA processes and what we what
we want to do is bring it back to the
beginning change the mindset to include
security at the inception of the project
so if you think about non-functional
requirements that's where we want to be
if you think about those first initial
meetings when developer or product
manager has got a crazy idea
now it doesn't only sync and speak to
the development team of how they can
implement this this actual functionality
of this new button but it's also
inclusive of the security there which is
yes you want to give access to all the
customers of the data without any kind
of authentication because that's going
to be practical okay a great and
security has always been saying no what
we want to do is we want to say yes yes
you can do things but we can do then
secure it so the way to do it is give
them your security policy give them your
requirements and then we'll start
syncing of security from from the start
of the project examples of how went
wrong I think there's just millions and
unfortunately the time of when did he go
right that's quite rare so number of
breaches that could have been avoided
it's it's again buyers of millions we've
we'll talk about it later successful
implementation of how we can do that
it's basically give your knowledge give
you tools and let the DevOps team let
the operational team run them there is
no reason for security team to run the
tooling apart to be completely on an
out-of-band management network rather
than using the methodologies of service
management that the traditional company
is using so it's it's used the tools
that you've got at your disposal ready
the CR C D for example is just fantastic
from security point of view it's instead
of doing your pen testing at the end of
traditionally that security has always
been about pen testing
so you finished all your product edges
yeah let's do a pen test let's get a
scoring then you end up with a list of I
don't know 700 bucks that they've got to
fix and the project manager is looking
at it by if I implement all those fixes
I'm gonna be light the company is not
going to be happy so let's just forget
it and we'll do that in your next
iteration but the next iteration was not
always in the same sense as DevOps we're
doing it's more about using the Sprint
so I hope that made sense it's really
about it's the culture of saying yes so
France well what's wrong with a retro
fitting or attempting to bolt on
security to a project when it's nearing
go life or even months it's been
released and we get a better picture of
where security defects are so if you
think of development lifecycle life
following a CR CD methodology security
will end up right at the end and you
will you will end up building all your
applications you've been you noggin
pages but for example nobody's thought
about the compliance requirements that
we've got or you've got the PCI
requirements that you've got and
suddenly you've realized that all the
credit card data has been stalled in a
text file because that's really easy to
actually access from an application
point of view that's how it's been
developed that's how the guys did it
when they've locked it
they put it on an Amazon bucket which
well most of the time is going to be
accessible by somebody because when you
implement a litigation that's gonna
create some issues for your development
team not necessarily understanding how
to manage mrs. H key correctly there's
been a few examples of companies that
got completely broke down so one a
Springs two Madden's Cook space so good
space was training company and they had
not only all all the application and all
the systems on an edible us bucket head
but also the backups unfortunately they
just put the keys the encryption key
into a public area so somebody quite
malicious basically got all of the keys
and just deleted everything so the
company's the backup this company closed
down in a matter of days and they
can't recover from this so they lost
everything that's the type of issues
that you've got we don't want to end up
like this she don't want to be the next
Yahoo if you think what yeah who is
doing at the moment they were to
actually reduce the price of self to
Verizon by some CR five hundred million
dollars that's quite significant answer
she bonuses of developers and security
people so we want to avoid that and
that's how really we want to we want to
give our knowledge from a security point
of view so security was always we're
sitting on an ivory tower nobody's going
to come close to us people who ask you
or what do we need to implement or
dedications or because that's written in
the security policy it's about why is it
written in a security policy why are
what are the consequences of it so it's
really just I'll strip yourself bare and
just explain to developers just like why
we're doing it we're not just a bunch of
people wanting to say no we just some
people to just actually just studied
security wherever we could actually
learn on the go and we need to give
these knowledge there is teaching
security person at code it's going to be
much harder than teaching a developer
how to do go to code to kill me so if I
take myself an example I couldn't argue
in code properly and if I want to
actually just go into this that's going
to take me years and years to every one
of that but through trainings that have
delivered to development teams they
picked up security really quickly and
application the quality of the
applications the results that you get
from a pen testing engagement before
security and after security being told
to deter problem teams is really
impressive yeah that's a good point
I've been called into so many
organizations there was development
teams struggling to produce solutions
with a measure of security in many of
these cases there was no security
focused people within the organisation
at all and for the cases where there are
other security people are always in
their own team separate from the
development teams what are the dangers
of siloing development and security
teams and how does DFC cops propose the
relationship between developers ops in
security professionals work
so I think the way to do it is start by
sitting with each other so I've done
lots of incident response lots of
forensics and you sitting in a glass box
somewhere never you can see actually
what you're doing but some of you dig a
bit further into it the administrator
which is in the operation center can
actually see everything on the screen
the actually data is that you can't hide
it and why should you just hide
everything yes you've got some
investigation which are quite data
sensitive especially about around
employment but all the rest really just
teaching to them there's nothing secrets
it is the only thing we're trying to do
is to avoid doing those breaches so
working in silos that never worked so
and one of the problems that we've got
as well is the quality of security
people and I've got to be careful here
but many as a sign maybe of the sea
serves in plenty of companies shall
steel running at the moment ceases are
coming from a management background
they're not gonna know anything
technically so they're not gonna be able
to defend it they're not gonna be able
to defend a budget they're not gonna be
able to teach the board what is the what
is the value associated with a bridge
that's that's what you need to do from
so I come from a really strong in
incident response point of view and
incident response has been used to
actually to protect complacency of other
teams so the development team is going
to be is gonna realize that there is a
problem or the pentest identified an
issue and just give it to as if
development team they're gonna say I
know it's just a lot of putting on
background it's just like as di our guys
do you actually just create some rules
on the ideas systems as it can
monetarist and they will tell us when
somebody's trying to to use this back
particular back functionality that's too
late already the speed of the computer
speed of the packet is not something a
human can actually follows his eyes or
follow is it sounds on a keyboard so
just automate it so you use the
methodology of automation for the
benefit of security so as we were
talking about the CIC day it's really
about you realise
that you've got those attacks coming on
against those particular aspect of your
website of your application including
part of the QA process just give the
give the attack pattern to your
developers for them to actually change
the application accordingly it's not
really hard and so you use there all
your security champion social security
champions is about security is gonna
teach one of the developers about about
security itself and just like how they
can disseminate this information to the
rest of the team so that that's one way
to do it and it's really about knowledge
sharing you can also walk an awesome CTF
makes them excited about that I used to
work in a different company to
high-frequency trading and the
gamification there was really about how
many bugs they can find in application
to the point where we've been running
those CTF for about two years and we
implemented about a scene we had loved
five known issues that we wanted them to
discover and one of the guards came back
was about ten of them and at this point
oh wow okay respect they got it and
that's and then they get excited and
those people that found those issues
there become your security champions
they realized that but they get a free
t-shirt but not only a free t-shirt they
can get a certification we respond to
them to actually learn more about
security have you found that um often a
security professionals that are are not
integrated into the development team
that are in a separate security team are
often I thought about as the developers
in in development teams
I was disdain in lack of respect is it
something you've come across Oh every
day every day it's the security team
normally the team there knows that the
team that says no they don't say
anything else when somebody approaches
desk is just oh no no no you can't do
that that's really crazy what kind of
idea is that
well suddenly you realize if you just
think about the business is business is
here to make some money so those
functionalities that project manager or
product manager is actually trying to
implement there is a good reason for
that they just really want to make
this is more more efficient or they want
to get some more customers so by giving
the ability to the security team as well
to be part of this decision to be part
of those discussions you you're helping
everybody to break those silos one of
the first thing I do when a drone
company as as a contractor is I try to
attend as many stands ups as I can to
understand what is in your eyes and what
what are we gonna do in the next 15 days
what do I need to consider for to help
the developers for them to get better
and that that's its security should not
be separated that's the that's the key
part of everything let's forget this
need to know well apart from a few of
areas where we've got to you yeah
restrict the information but just not
give your knowledge it doesn't cost you
anything it's it's it's for everybody
this knowledge can you explain now what
shifting security lift means yes has
been a big buzzword at moments so
shifting security left simply is so if
we start from left to right to do your
development and as we're talking at the
beginning you've got security which is
bolted on at the end and it's just like
I've put a badge and some said yeah
you've been certified well done it's
really you start from the nfl's so you
start from your non-functional
requirements you start from your
requirements fans where you explain okay
we're going to be dealing with financial
data right guys we've got to think about
the PCI requirements not the PCI
requirements and version one which was
you need to verifiable but doesn't need
to have any network going through we
need to think about the new type of
compliance here which is like how do we
actually implement security that makes
change and that's that's that's really
the essence of it which is just like
start from beginning with all the
different teams be part of the change
so isn't shifting security lifts going
to slow the development process down and
ultimately cost the organization more I
think initially there's going to be a
learning curve where so
this security person is going to be
asking lots of questions as usual we do
love to ask plenty of questions so there
is going to be an initial lag into the
development the development process but
if you think about the cost of
implementing security later on that's
completely different it's just a lot of
fixing a bug in production that's going
to cost you a fortune so that's gonna be
we're gonna have to stop production and
we're gonna have to redo QA processing
we'd have to redo all our artifacts we
have to do all your version control
again you'll have to do all your
documentation if you do it at the
beginning
once everything is just being built
you've got the ability to just reduce
this cost intimately so by shifting left
your security by discovering issues and
bugs at an earlier stage you can easily
incorporate part of your QA process and
the company will actually grow to the
additional lag that you will experience
into those requirements meeting that's
going to go down but also the cost of
fixing security is gonna be much lower
so it's ultimately you're gonna gain
some money I haven't seen any of my
customers that we're not pleased with
the implementation and especially the
product managers they just love that and
say I don't need to hear about security
I don't need to hear about a traditional
pen testing that is gonna occur there a
month three months six months nine it's
it becomes built in so you build in your
security to just make sure it doesn't
cost you tests at the end so we've had
lists of the most commonly exploited
defects like sins top 25 in the OWASP
top 10 since about 2003 the same types
of trivial defects are still the most
often exploited but our development
teams are still introducing the same
defects to the solutions they're
delivering is deep sigh cops the answer
in Y so deficit cops is part of the
answer there so cops is really
emphasizing the fact that you've got to
do for example you've got to do shred
modeling and threat modeling is actually
quite fun and and if you get your
development teams on board of just
understanding how you do you use rate
modeling
they're gonna start thinking about it
and they can incorporate those test
bottle QA it's really easy so all you
who are top 10 and top 25 you can
actually just not incorporate part of
your QA process give them the ability to
test it for themselves so one of the
best time ads in in a company was we
have given all my security tools to the
dev ops Carson it's just like new cars I
don't need to run any of the
vulnerability management services I
don't need to just like be there to
actually press the button you do it
because you're gonna need to do it at
scale at speed in an intuitive processes
my security team is going to be busy
doing some other things we want once you
actually give access to those tools so
security team just fixed requirements
for them to just love to to to match so
we're gonna say are you allowed X number
of defects you allowed X number of
security issues usually should be close
to zero but that's I think the important
is it's not the zero defect it's the
zero violation so what we gonna build
and that's why we're always talking
about six chief security to the left
we're fond of start where you build your
application you've done your threat
modeling you've done all your testing if
you haven't got any variation by the end
of the day you know what you've got you
know what your finishing with then you
actually combine this with metadata that
you've been accumulating all the way
through your CI CD that's going to
benefit all your your our team so your
incident response team is just going to
have the ability to actually dig into
this metadata and say I've got a problem
is deserver because this is the type of
services or software this is a level of
which is running you've got the ability
to actually do an incident response
really quickly but if you go even
further
you'll DevOps guysyou operations now
actually reconfigure to save that
themselves because you've just given
them the methodology so if you think
about those different type of
methodology of of threat modeling law
past our stride it's really about
attacking your systems and just see how
it reacts then you incorporate it part
of your QA to
doesn't need to be part of that at all
you stopping slowing down the project
which is key for everybody it's security
has got a bad name to be honest let's
let's let's be completely honest we have
we haven't been the most efficient type
of industry but lots of people made lots
of money out of creating some tools
which are bolting on and you end up with
stalls built on Lego type of security
rather than just actually wanting to
change things and that's the aim of
deaths of cops we just like take our
knowledge change it we want to do things
differently we're just here to help
we're not here to say no security
exploitation continues to advance in the
attackers constantly developing more
advanced attacks but most of the
development teams I work with still
don't know what a trivial defect and
exploit looks like a little own how to
prioritize and potentially fix it Ken
devs AQAP's
save us from this situation if so how
and and do you have any success stories
now we have seen a development team in
the organization transformed from a poor
performing low security unit to a high
performing security conscious team in
organization so there's a cop's again
will help in today so make people aware
of what what does those security of well
as consequences what are the
consequences of an SQL injection attack
or cross-site scripting and you'll
perfectly correct in the fact that most
of the developers don't understand it
don't even know about it and that's at a
developer's level so once you've got a
breach that's affecting your company and
you've got usually you will have a
security analyst standing in front of
the board and telling them hey guys we
had their we had a cross-site scripting
and somebody stole all our money and the
board is just looking at is always
talking about and it's just like you've
got to do this democratization of
security you've got to change it and and
it's really just use plain words use the
same words as everybody else and he's
just about the guy actually got the
crown jewels all right okay got it
that's quite easy so success stories is
this quite a few success stories is just
one of them where we are to implement a
DDoS protection and what would be in
last is
the rooters were just actually not able
to cope over to a certain level it's
some of the key things that you found
when you're reading RFC's it's it's
quite interesting and the developer he's
not gonna read the RFC really he's just
like people like security people that
I've got I'm not gonna say enough times
on the hand but it's just a passion to
actually read between the lines to just
understand what are the interesting
details of the protocol and we were
really struggling from security point of
view just like this constant details and
how to just mitigate it and really good
DevOps guys managed to combine
information that was coming from our
network behavior systems
towards the rooters so they were able to
say where we're gonna reach this
threshold this is the switch that you're
gonna make over this is you gonna you're
gonna change the bandwidth available for
example you're gonna change to what
server the information is going to be
processed onto and that was not done
from the security guards the security
guys only said to them that's the
problem and remember that network
security and network engineer
specialized in network engineering so
use the information let them make the
decision the same as a developer it's
let them make the right decision on how
to write the codes slight caveat here is
just like we've got to tell them which
function is good and which one is bad
but again that's down to us to actually
teach them well why you shouldn't use
printf exit right cetera so it's and
it's really about communication and we
are saying at the beginning and
entertain them make them realize what
happened when you use these kind of
things and all this you can link it back
to yes there's a postman I said yes it
does cost money it does cost money to
actually teach people and we open to
university we know it cost money and you
don't stop learning when you come out of
university you do that all the way
through your life so everything that you
learn give it to the other people it's
it's not your knowledge I'll make it
public write the blog about it make
people interested in it that's us and I
think that's the key to make security
better
for the company and for the greater good
so do you have any tips on how you can
transform poor performing team that has
I guess minimal focus on security to a
high performing team with a good focus
on security so there's two aspect to
that question first one I'm going to
think about is just poor poor performing
security teams which are actually not
good enough to actually teach the rest
of the business of how to do security
properly there's a few answers to that
I'm gonna skip the first one because I'm
not gonna make me a lot of friends but
it's really about just like what are you
defending learn what you're defending
once you understand what you're
defending understand what type of
regulations you've got to comply with if
you look at the other side which is poor
performance team or not necessary poor
performance but how you your development
teams not really understand security
here and again I'm gonna repeat the CTF
here just inter exchange the teams make
this a situates team part of the
development teams so break it out don't
let them just like be on the ivory
towers we're saying before it's just
luck be happy to be part of the
development teams and understand what
they're trying to do speak to your
project manager speak to your product
manager you product manager actually is
quite interesting security and security
nowadays become this kind of added value
for companies they're starting to
understand that yes you can provide
great functionality you can just provide
access to all the information of the
world but if you provide it securely
that's going to be your selling point
and everything is about selling
everything is about making some money
let's be completely honest here so if
you can actually just build this in you
your winner that's distinct and one of
them I think one of the way to think
about security is the same as
sustainable agriculture so you've got
your soil and you can get whatever you
want from your soil which is like a to
set and level and as the level of
populations actually
we wanted to make it more efficient we
wanted to be able to grow in the top of
grain anywhere we wanted so we had this
great idea about fertilizers oh yeah
okay right we can fight against these
bug and we're just going to put this
fertilizer think about your fertilizer
as your pen tester and it's just coming
in they just put the fertilizer and
really lost like 15 years later some but
not seen is growing anymore
that's what happened you you your pen
tester and I was a pen tester myself so
I can talk about you just come in you
just do your job you just give you a
recommendation and you go away and
that's how deficit cops is trying to do
it is just what we're here for the long
term we are here to understand that no
there is no point trying to grow this
type of grain onto this type of soil we
need to understand the type of grain
which is growing in this soil and how we
can make the best out of it so there
might be pushing it are just not
sustainable agriculture and and and I
think we need to think about it that way
as in we need it you need your
architecture you need your security to
make things better so let's work
together so I found that by adding a
specific set of our processes and
practices like security regression
testing and security focus TDD and evil
test conditions and a bunch of other
things have actually improved I would
turn on investment for the development
teams are delivering projects so that
can actually deliver projects faster and
then the byproduct is actually a lot
fewer bugs is it something you've come
across yes yeah no definitely I'm so
lost but we're really good to actually
provide all this information for example
those those little tooling those those
teaching ability for example I give the
juice shop to people just let them play
with it let them understand how does it
react how does the system react but also
as you were saying you TDD are just
really if you do that this is going to
be a to happen once you you can so
you've got this great thing from
security where we've been monitoring
we've been loving monitoring and
accumulating data and terabyte of data
and nobody's actually doing anything
with it actually if you analyze this
data you've got the ability
to see the type of attacks coming
through you can see the patterns give
disinformation to the development team
so many many years ago I used to work
for a big ISP and we reserved I think
there was about 1 million ipv4 addresses
just geared towards creating honey pots
and those holy pots were actually a
wealth of data yes the rest of the
population in the world is completely
locked come to hate that we've been
using design peas just by ourselves
where everybody's running out of them
but by using this information were able
to actually give it back to the
antivirus vendors and say this is a new
strain of viruses that we can see at the
moment this is a new trend of attacks
that we're seeing at the moment so I
think the more people going to do that
but not from a commercial point of view
that's the problem it's just like
everything is really commercial and yes
we look up to make some money but the
more we make this information available
to everybody the more we're going to be
improved
those tdd and the better the return on
investment you're going to get on on
security its security needs to change
from making money from themselves to
saving money from the company it's we
all in a security world with we all will
say it just is nothing better than a
breach that's when we're getting all the
money in the world that's where we're
getting all the funding but we shouldn't
wait for that it's quite easy to
calculate the cost of a bridge before
well at a high level before he actually
happen and don't use that to scare
people but use it as an investment money
to teach the rest of your team then you
can just like gather all this data and
make the developer better better
developer better
so one in one of the companies that
worked and the best was when we managed
to reduce the number of security
monitoring folks from from 10:00 to 5:00
from 10:00 to 2:00 and that's really
good because everybody else is doing it
you incorporate you work as part of
somebody else's workload you use the
tools so you can see your pen testers
you're going to realize that they've got
this information
they can actually send it part of your
rally or part of any kind of bug
tracking facility for them to actually
work upon use the tools from the rest of
your company don't isolate yourself we
just like you own private tools that
just nobody can access it's just not
give this information away and as you
were saying you're gonna see the return
on investment investment really quickly
I found that the closer you get are the
security people to the development
process are the cheaper other
development process becomes so like you
can have like your external development
team but still part of the same
organization and it's more expensive
than having security but are built into
the development team and then you've got
like you external pentesters which are
not part of the organization and then
it's even more expensive again is that
something you have found yeah I think
one of the problems we've got is all
those big system integrators is going to
take and sorry all system integrators
it's gonna take a while to actually
change the mentality that they've got
they realized that they can get
workforce from there from there in the
coding the same way and they not sync
and they've got the security team which
is completely separated we're really
there is a great synergy between those
two team is just aa mix them up make
them part of one team maybe instead of
having like a developer team and a
security team you have team which are
driven by product this is the
functionality that we've got to build
together so I need in this team a
developer product manager project
manager security folk and I need to
Representative to the board here you go
then you've got it
but the my deals are one step completely
forgotten here but instead of making it
as one team fighting against each other
that doesn't work it's you create
tension and once you've got tension
you've got this this really bad
competition between the team the
developer is gonna tell you hey we're
just creating money and you security is
just costing us some money so bad yes
with yes we are okay agreed hands up but
by working together
we're working for this company X and we
making a software or an application
better so it's we should all look at the
the outcome of what we're trying to do
rather than just identifying ourselves
to a development team or security team
support for SC radio comes from the
O'Reilly velocity conference join over
2,000 developers and engineers in San
Jose from June 19th through the 22nd to
learn how resilience engineering can
make your systems more scalable reliable
and efficient get the latest on
containers micro services infrastructure
cloud devops systems engineering
security and more while you meet experts
and network with peers use discount code
SE 22 save 20% on your gold silver or
bronze pass
that's SE 2-0 get all the details at
velocity conf calm /c a safe transfer um
you mentioned a juice shop before can
you just explain for the listeners what
that is yes so the juice shop does want
a project from one of the many projects
or morris which is an intentionally
intentionally insecure web app for
security training you've got those
you've got many of them you've got
before the acme bank that them from a
very poor application and this one is
really written in not yes and angular
and it's orientated users not giving
them challenges and understand how they
can exploit different security
vulnerability it's it's helping for
those CTF and that's some of the great
things really is that OSP is doing it's
really about giving the ability to
somebody to learn so does I use them
quite a lot as in hey guys come come and
hack me so come and hack me come come on
understand what is the issue and that's
what we're saying at the beginning about
giving the developers the ability to
just law have a bit of fun it is
actually quite funny when you just
manage to exploit somebody and so no you
just pop a shell and just like yes got
it and and that's what the juice shop is
about
it's really about helping people
understand security how they can exploit
it and how to make things better yes
it's an excellent learning tool what are
the costs of introducing DFC cops our
practices into an organisation in here -
are the benefits outweigh the costs so
the cost is worried because we're saying
is gonna be about the initial lag I
can't really put an actual number of it
because it's going to depend from every
every company but that's that's gonna
you're gonna have to slow down the
organization beginning you've got to
understand where they trying to go and
that's when the development process is
going to slow down a little bit there's
gonna be some learning curve there's
gonna be those dis introductions as
we're saying is juice shop part of those
part of this work wisdom which the
developers so but yes this initial cost
is going to be is gonna be felt
especially by the project manager so
you're gonna have the project manager on
your back on a daily basis so you better
be a good friend with him or make good
friend with him
but then you end up with you you end up
with less attacks so you you you end up
like the understanding was your attack
surface then you end up having the
ability to understand the type of
attacks which are going to go through
but you developers are gonna understand
what is dis attack surface and what type
of attacks can actually the application
can be subject to and what kind of
defenses they can actually build into so
ultimately you reducing the cost as
we're saying before you reducing the
cost of bolting security at the end
stopping all development processes and
having to beg your project manager for a
three-month delay because everybody
forgot about the pen testing ability so
it's you you will end up with less
redundant code the lesser attack surface
you'll end up with coding the right
saying you will endure ways reducing the
number of functions they are you doing
so less thinking less ability so yes you
developer is
for the creativity and you should never
stop that but it's your job as a
security guard to understand what
they're trying to achieve and learn what
they're learning it's the same way
they've got to learn about security he's
learned about the new function engine
learn about the new languages that
they've got and so there is going to be
discerning curve cost I can't actually
give you a number but ultimately I
assure you you can only you're going to
save some money if you implement deficit
cost methodology so do you have any
examples of organizations that you've
witnessed or been a part of or even like
been an advocate for and basically
converted them from a traditional sort
of security reactive focus to something
like div C cops there are a few
companies so a fewer quant well-known
like Etsy Capital One and other ones I
can't mention the name and but it's
they've been they've been at the
forefront of making the change they've
been in the forefront of understanding
okay the company wants to move to cloud
how can we use the cloud to do that how
can we use a kubernetes monitoring as a
triple-a T how can we use the
functionality that we've got within the
cloud to actually help our developers
not do silly sense and vice versa
it's just how can a developer help me to
build a good security application which
is going to answer to their problem and
it's I've seen companies where it's
quite amazing not seeing everybody in
the company are you going to be talking
about 40,000 people doing stand-ups
every day including the lawyers so you
will just walk around the floor and
you've got like a bunch of lawyers doing
you stand up in the morning so what is
it doing and and that's where you can
see the power of it and the power of
does really good implementations and the
security folks just floating about
providing this information providing
those requirements to your discards and
by using all these iterative processes
by using the cloud
technologies we've got the ability to
change things
one of the biggest problem that we've
got moment is IOT and we all know that
because IOT is is just really a
commodity so it's companies have been
using really cheap code that you can
bolt on unto any kind of device to make
it IOT and to make it like internet
capable I think the way to think about
it for you and me that's going to be
just add Bluetooth to it that's gonna
make it sexy and and it used to be like
this and it's just like are you can have
every scene - so you get bluetooth to it
that's perfect put it in a car and and
the a day I don't know if you remember
the one where there there was something
about the the ability to measure how
inflated your your tires on the car
where via bluetooth they realize that
you can actually just use that traction
you deflate it great and I think with
facing exactly the same thing with the
IOT which is just life you've got those
those hair brush that got an IOT just
love why why do you DD what who needs to
know how many times do I brush my hair
or my beard and how strong do I do it
it's it's totally irrelevant so I think
it's again a trend that we're facing at
the moment and why you need a bit of
regulation but I think let's not do the
regulation again mark PCI let's not do
the regulation like toasters everything
that we had was in medical industry we
need to really change it and think about
it it's I think one of the the best
example that we add is the medical
industry we all know that those things
needs to be patched well ok great and
you will have you touched on security
guy she's going to say you need to patch
this his ventilator which is keeping
this person aloft
so right ok so if I patch it I need to
bring in a flying and this person's
gonna die
ok I didn't think about that one so and
and that's what we're saying before
which is just like need to understand
what your company is building you need
to understand what you are defending and
how you need to change your approach
accordingly
so in the medical industry things
actually changing they actually trying
to make some new regulation I see Munich
on in the US Congress
so I think we should watch out these
things quite closely
the same for IOT s because it's it's a
bit ridiculous
it's remember an IOT is something which
is going to be accessible by everybody
else so it's it's not going to be really
stylish by default again implementing
security on it as more code mode testing
unless you do it from the beginning were
you thinking right I want to create a
hairbrush which is going to be connected
to the Internet
secure it so only I can know about it
still don't know why but it's only you
gonna be able to have this information
that's the same as everything else which
is like yes you can store my data but
prove me it is secure prove me you're
holding it securely which most of the
time they con do yeah I think as users
we need to demand a lot more from IOT
devices in terms of security so where is
the cheapest point in the software
development lifecycle to deal with all
types of defects including security and
can you explain why it's the cheapest
point so the cheapest point is at the
requirement phase it's really it's where
we linked up into the ship security to
the left which is this is the data we're
gonna deal with this is a functionality
we're going to give with this is the
information that we want to provide it
in person so that's when security needs
to be invited at the table for those
projects yes you can't have as many
security people as you've got developers
that person doesn't make any financial
sense but we need to just explain house
if we need to provide this information
and be clear to everybody right some NFR
so everybody writes on security
principles so those security principles
I think last time I wrote them I wrote
some for for an organ Allah sorry
government organization there was 15 of
them and that's it and actually
everything every functionality that a
developer will want to build can refer
to those 15 principles to make an
application secure so it's all about
give away your security policy and again
just use this security policy to bash
people around the head teach them while
it's here that's cheaper that's much
cheaper and then suddenly we're not
going to end up with security being a
dying breed we're gonna end up with
security being more about hunting for
threats understanding more and
communicating them accordingly lots of
traditional security has been the echo
chamber they own echo chambers it oh wow
look how great I am I've I've managed to
deflate those those tires with this new
exploit that ratings laughing great
what's the solution how do we fix it
where do we fix it and as we were saying
we fix it right at the beginning by
saying I should not prefer give the
ability for anybody else apart from me
to deflate or inflate my tires
that's kind of logic and so it's to
conclude is really a just yes do it at
the beginning it's gonna be cheaper
fixing an issue in production recalling
a hundred and fifty million automobile
cars it's not really effective that's
the cost of bad security implementation
that's billions and that that's the
problem so if you think of your scandal
that you've got at the moment what they
call the diesel gate somebody was quite
clever and just created this piece of
software no sale I know if you get
tested just say everything is cool there
is no security problem here there's no
emissions now it's costing them billions
and billions to actually correct that
maybe some part of the business are
gonna go down and that's that's what
we've got to watch out for that's what
we've got to make the business aware is
just like you can't really lie to the
public well you can lie for said
sometimes that works it's we always seen
it but ultimately you're gonna place a
cost for it and you're not gonna pay the
cost once you're gonna pay the cost by
billions and companies will go down
hopefully not all the car manufacturers
are just playing the same games but
that's what we've got to watch out for
can you think of any other benefits of
bringing the security focus from the end
of the software development lifecycle up
front door than the development teams
iterations
and do you have any success stories
there other than the one I've said
really it's you gonna you gonna you're
going to see less of security and if
you're a developer really that's a
benefit trust me I think we all know it
having the security folks just like on
your desk every single day because they
found a new issue it's it becomes
quantities and also as a security folk
really it's just like going to the same
person going to the same team with the
same problem on every single application
every single project I think you should
look at yourself in the mirror and say
maybe I'm not communicating it properly
maybe that's my fault
so actually just like change the
conversation just speak to developers
say what what don't you understand not
what don't you understand about what I
said is just like how can I help you to
understand my requirements it's turn the
tables around you know you not as a
security folks you not the better person
not necessarily the the developer is
really trying to do his job by security
who's trying to do our job but let's not
confront each other let's work together
and all the companies will have
implemented their circles you've ended
up with some tensions at the beginning
but which we quickly resolved by
understanding by making the other people
understand the need for it how cheaper
this is gonna be and how you not gonna
see as much of me which is always a
benefit for a bit
do you have any stories we're
implementing DC cops practices has
caused negative results so so more time
spent focusing on security means less
time coding right unless you develop
security as code which was one of the
first principles from from there's a cop
so of Shannon leads that created the
organization the foundation of Desa cops
the moto of Def sakata's security as
code which is you Gaza coding so let me
actually change my security as code
and you can implement it part of your
application make the application defend
itself become anti fragile that's that's
the point it is just like you you need
to benefit from the information you're
going to get so an attacker is just
gonna leave a trace he's going to leave
a pattern is going to leave an
indication of what is going to happen
use this data and this data transform
this code is going to make the
application better so now having got
really a lot of a experience where wait
we'd gone wrong at all it always worked
and I think that's why we see more and
more people about deficit cops and just
like how to implement it and how to work
together because it's beneficial for
companies unless I don't know I'm always
happy to hear different things but it's
ivanson any any any adverse effect of of
implementing security from the beginning
so how do you go about I'm changing the
mindsets of the traditional thinking
managers developers and security pros
that want to I continue to throw
deliverables over the wall to the next
team rather than combining all necessary
skills into each team show them how much
she costs and uses standard terms of
what they're saying just delays it's
think about a traditional like waterfall
and when you arrive into your critical
path and everybody's less open arms and
and usually just like in your critical
path somewhere between the day before
release and release that's where you've
got a security tape here show them
actually just like this this should be
somewhere else this should be much
bigger or actually we can make it better
did this security which is like just in
a critical path that's should be some
somewhere else there should be in every
part of your sprint there should be
built in your processes that should be
built in your development processes
that's it's not really it's not it's not
magic it's just like the quicker and the
more often you're going to do it the
more issues you can
find the less this is going to cost you
to actually remediate them
it's instead of completely constantly
are branching out branching in you've
got the ability to just long make people
understand why security is there how
they can implement it and automate it so
I think you need to move away from all
this big pen task which I think in three
months and just like one months of
reporting and two months of discussion
around the table why nobody should
actually implement any of it
which is it's not beneficial for anybody
so if you actually build it in your code
if you actually just incorporate your
security part of your development
processes part of you your project your
project manager your project manager
should know about security should
understand the value and one of the best
way to actually show them is the delays
incurred by not implementing security
all the delays incurred by look guys
we've got to put the web like website
offline because we've just been hacked
how many millions you're gonna lose
working in financial sector for a long
time it's if you're not online if you
can't trade that's gonna cost a lot and
you're talking millions millions protect
that's that's one way to show it and and
usually you'll comes back to money and
time which is wasted and think about the
the AWS outage that you had the other
day where that was a typical example of
no redundancy has been implemented where
people rely on the redundancy built into
it upon us to actually monitor the
things and that was the best time for
the developers and for any any operation
guys because there was just like I can't
tell you what's wrong because I can't
tell you what's wrong because we put all
our eggs in the same basket and if
somebody build the architecture
correctly they would have been able to
say well again we need this kind of out
of band management we need to understand
how we can just change it how we can
monitor it without relying totally on
one technology or without relying
totally on one company so architecture
is also really key of how you can
implement security and how you're going
to run a company efficiently so I'm
thinking I want to embrace the DVI ops
culture in practice
how do we combined Eve sick in ops
there's a new team that's coming from
the traditional approaches where do we
start
okay so the first thing is make them sit
down together so you know all those
partition walls that we all love the
nursing just like nobody can actually
see what you're doing you can put the
pictures from your kids everywhere it's
just now bring them down not not the
pictures of your kids but actually those
walls which are there and make them
communicate what what are the best way
to communicate is just those stand up
stand ups is really good methodology
where we've got to actually the ability
to express what we're working on and how
somebody can actually help us work more
efficiently in it
so it's mostly about communication and
advance warning it's about you product
managers being all encompassing of all
those themes and and just like making
sure that they don't forget security
start by building non-functional
requirements with all the different
teams just like not just as I was saying
before not just the security ones burden
the non-functional requirements from
from a DevOps point of view from from a
development point of view and also from
a security operational point of view so
the security operations traditionally
has been just sitting you desk we've got
17 screens around you none of them
actually using the same metrics none of
them are using the same data points so
to combine those things just like there
is going to be a pattern there is a way
to combine this information coming from
the IDS with with the rest of the logs
than you getting so it's really about
transparency it's about giving the
ability for people to see what you're
saying and make them make them aware of
it make them aware that oh yes you've
got this beta and I remember one day
where one of the flowers asked us and
say hey guys can we get access to your
IDs data so the first and so on to the
war what do you want that it's all
secrets and it realizes just about
actually they can benefit from it
because they're gonna see what problems
we
then they're gonna understand why we
swing these things over the fence and
you're just like hey go and fix that
because we can see that you've got this
type of attack which has matched a new
pattern developed by the new snort tar
ball that we downloaded this morning as
well yeah but actually we just tailored
we just changed the protocol in a
certain way so that's why you're getting
a false positive here so bring down
those partitions make them talk with
each other it's communication is really
undervalued and that's one of the
biggest probably knows of companies
we've just we traded two silos silos yes
there was good reason for those why good
reason the way of some reason why they
were creating can measures put it to BT
you can measure the effectiveness of a
company of a certain team but actually
you should measure the productivity as
by the quality of the work that you have
shaved together not by an interview team
is producing those developers will
develop lot 57 functionality in a day
great but then you realize that as
always the security team has been
completely understaffed and there was
one poor guy which is trying to analyze
everything at the same time was just
getting data for 170 idea sensors from
around the world and can't make sense of
it so most of the times they're just
going to let go of it they're not going
to see the pattern before an incident is
occurring to make you developers part of
security maybe security guards partly
developers make them work together it's
it's actually not complicated so how do
we go about I'm shifting the security
focus left who are bringing it up front
with an H in every sprint be more
transparent so it's as we're saying
before it's really about make yourself
part of those discussions understand
what they're trying to build understand
how how and what functionality what
function they want to implement make
some research its security folks we've
got to we've got to go back to our boots
quite a lot and just make some research
on what what they're trying to implement
what are they trying to achieve so
that's always the question asked which
is not okay
to do that but what are you trying to
achieve what is YouTube it go and then
you realize that the ultimate goal is
for them to get more data up great
actually I would love a bit more data so
it's be part of this initiative is
discussions and don't be afraid to ask
questions it's not deal good questions
as usual same luck what are you trying
to do that but more about let me help
you how can we work together to actually
make it more secure why are you trying
to use this functionality we've got this
data already no you don't need to
collect all this data you don't need to
log everybody's passwords there is no
need for it especially not in plain text
explain them why and then you will you
will actually just like you're gonna
save some money you're gonna make
everybody as happy as we're saying just
like cash limit earlier before they
start implementing blue to use on your
tires that's that's the best way to do
it
so what challenges in obstacles to teams
face and moving security to the front of
the development process with an each and
every sprint in here can they go by
overcoming these assume I think that's
the traditional design and coding that
has been the mindset of people that has
been that is one of the biggest
challenges that we're facing the silo
mentality the fact that the people are
still thinking of Q as a certain place
Security's at the end just rejiggered
just think about how we can use the
situated processes for each of them for
all of us for our own benefits so every
time you've got a development team which
is building a new functionality just
like security should be there at the
same time testing falls at four for any
security issues then provide the
feedback in a timely manner but this is
gonna speed up everybody she's going to
speed up the resolution time she's gonna
speed up the communication she's going
to speed up the presen and this is going
to speed up ultimately just deployment
in production but don't forget the
traceability of all of them so we were
talking earlier about metadata
just how we can use this metadata for
incident response for developers so it's
it's important to actually capture this
data so people can actually benefit from
it it's it's it's embraced to change as
we always say it's one of them a company
they move to as changes energizes us and
there was a different background for
that is because they changed names about
15 times in five years but actually just
like it's really an energizing people
who learn about those new technologies
when when I first came across many years
ago on CRC day across the RCD I said
that's brilliant that's really that's
helping me from a security point of view
to actually get better quicker and from
security from what from a development
point of view dough is just long amazing
they've got the ability to just like
code more and just test more and just
like see better faster quicker result
which ultimately it's going to provide
your company more monic which most other
companies than what they're doing except
if you in a nonprofit organization like
the circles here have you managed to
bring security skills to within
development teams when traditionally
they haven't been there before it's all
about it's all been about training so
it's really about teaching them was you
know it's challenging it's really
challenging in the beginning where they
don't want to understand why are you
trying to implement those further checks
they don't understand why you're trying
to slow them down because they haven't
seen the outcome and as we were saying
before is just like an incident is the
best equality that what happened for
situating usually the creation of
security team starts from an incident
that occurred so you've got massive
incidents suddenly the seesaws I said no
CEO is gonna say wow I've read this
article on CEO magazine X and we need to
implement security we're going to start
by monitoring everything and we're gonna
slow down the processes we can implement
some pentesting at the end and
everybody's gonna be happy so we love
some certifications it's just one okay-y
that doesn't really work though we can
why do certifications and actually
that's one thing which are changing some
interesting companies actually said find
the works where they're saying I will
review your code and for every line of
code I've reviewed if you get an
incident related to the code of Refuge I
provide you this insurance of X million
to actually pay for your insulin
response that's that's a game-changer
that's really security just taking
ownership of their work and I think
that's a really good way of doing it
which is we do what we're doing for good
reason and we can certify own work and
we certify own work by just charging
ourself in case it goes wrong but again
that's traditional security um it's and
those pentester which are coming here
they should not sit down with your
security team aware they're just like
the olden echo chambers I've got this
new tool and just doing that oh wow
that's really sexy it's just like no
sit-down with developers to actually do
your your your pen testing don't do it
remotely all the time yes we will like
to work from the beach and just like
just throw over some some some problems
and development II go and sit down with
them show them what we're doing it's I
remember doing a pen test
15 years ago when you just standing up
on dates and it's 17 degrees and you're
there with your growth and the
developers actually came with me today
some time because they wanted to see
everything they wanted to understand why
I was using the switches on nmap they
wanted to understand it next things are
new next time I came to do the pen test
the girls actually just already run all
the tools and done all methodology that
I've done so a barrier at anything to
find I was really frustrating but that's
make them interested just not
necessarily gamified but give them a new
skill and to be overt like a developer
they've got security Till's cuz it's
security skills that's gonna be great
for the market everybody's going to want
to hide so what about establishing a
security champion within the development
team hit
you found that it's been successful
lifting the security focus within the
development team yeah it's been really
great there is the problem is the
continuity of it it's a bit like your
fire warden in the company so you've got
the guy that has good lives been here
for 25 years and because he's been here
for 25 years and he knows all the exits
in the building just earned this like
fire water and stuff there is this
complacency and that's one of the scene
that we've got to fight against which is
just know you've got to always reinvent
yourself and training your situation
pian making them rotate just don't give
them like a little statue or badge and
everything else yeah you're a security
champion now you've got to constantly
train them take them with you on
conferences take them with you on
training take them with you on the
journey of how you implement security
how you learned about those new tooling
and how how to break them how to fix
them so it's it's a good starting point
but never forget that you've got to
constantly train them it's if not there
is going to be a fire somewhere and the
fire water is gonna say I don't worry
that's driving a cigarette as usual next
is EAC and yo esters lot trips add like
a false fire alarm actually it's not
it's not a false fire alarm that's there
was a fire this time and everybody burns
in the building that's not good and that
can happen in two ways security
champions often developers are focused
on delivering business value in security
experts are usually focused on pushing
that value back because they see defects
in it developers are often the yeast
people in security you're often than
know people do you have an example of
here now you've been able to make these
too often opposing disciplines
complement strengthen and empower each
other I've seen one of the best time
what I said earlier is when I gave away
all the tools from the security team and
as a as a side effect like most of the
team got made redundant including myself
but that's just good consequence in a
way that's a good achievement because
you don't need to have to security has
always been about as
said that no people and we've been
trying to identify this shadow IT
actually we created the shadow RT we
traded the shadow ID by creating our
support organization within the security
teams so who's gonna maintain the IDS
system the security why should a dealer
there should be normal Ops guys just
like maintaining the tooling so it's
it's about understanding up to what
level they can see so maybe you don't
want them to see every IDs data where
it's after you've just decrypted or you
SSL channel and they've got the ability
to actually harvest all the cards but
while your security team should say
they've got there is a good reason but
how do you certify somebody to have
access to this data and to give way
older students give away to your
developers to you QA process your
celebrity management so stripe modeling
work with them to implement it don't
don't do it in isolation never this is
never gonna work
if you do it in isolation that's the
problem we're trying to fix at the
moment which is shifted to the left
scale up the people you've got to scale
up your developers you've got to scale
up to your UPS guys to actually
understand why are you monitoring it how
are you monitoring it and what you do in
case of an incident yes security
professionals especially from an
incidence response point of view our
partically skilled in a certain certain
way but it doesn't mean that you have
Scott Scott used TCP dump to actually
provide you this packet capture or even
better just automate it or let them know
what they've got to see give them some
filters on Wireshark of how they can
analyze this data for your benefit
that's in there's been a few times where
ops cars actually found the issue before
my team's found it at first feeling a
bit awkward it was just like oh well
maybe I should have such a big team and
we shouldn't go in those expensive
trainings like $6,000 above and then you
realize well I can use those guys I can
reduce all my costs
I can read
use all my workforce because I've got
the skills somewhere else so as you were
saying before ultimately you end up
saving money by training everybody by
shifting security to the left by
teaching them by implementing the
security champions and developing the
security as code
I'm not saying completely or to make
your security team because it's quite
important but there's plenty of things
that we don't need to do in isolation so
it's it's really promotes inclusion
rather than exclusion and work together
for the greater good
he along his deep-set kahn been running
deficit : my head has been running for
quite a while but physically started in
seeing the first event was on 20th of
October 2015
so deficit Khan started out of
frustration by frustration of exactly
what we've been talking about which is
security not being taken seriously how
do we automate it and lots of read good
discussion with Shannon leads from the
deficit cops organization then I
realized there is nothing no security
conference which is not his own echo
chamber I'm not going to name them
because the old really good conferences
about end at the mall but none of the
conferences were actually how do we
change it how do we how would we change
security how do we make it better more
accessible for everything so that sitcom
stands for development security
conference there's been many names on
the saying there is last SEC develops
there's a cops upstairs egg extract
cetera and jessica has been running now
for two and a half years that to to
successful event in London where the
attendees have been doubling every year
we just run our first event in Singapore
as well which was really good and kami
were here as as a trainer which was
really good to have you next steps for
their second is so be planning debt
second Boston which is going to take
place in the second week of September
this time waving for quite a lot of
people and
few days to cutter for Eastern West
Coast Oh same time and more towards you
we can build desa con Sydney and so
that's going to be enough spring for you
so there's going to be a lot of
beginning of end of November there are
about some requests for Desa con India
it's really going all over the place and
what we're trying to do is provide the
knowledge to everybody for really cheap
price the aim is just make it affordable
make it accessible it's I'm sure like me
you've done orders situated trainings
where it's about six thousand dollars to
attend you do five days and at the end
you've got really nice educate they
respond you but not enough value not
enough practical value so that was there
was there was the premise of deficit
come now we can people go to find out
more about the DC cops and Eve sitcom so
deficit cops is a nonprofit organization
which is running on deficit cops top org
we totally building some curriculum as
where we asking people to actually help
us to build some of those project of
security as code def second is running
on desert calm would come just about to
release a new version of the website
which is going to cover all different
kind of sorry edit point yeah so we're
just about to release a new website to
actually cover all the different vents I
will also announce deficit Khan training
curriculum which is going to be around
two days where we actually taking you on
a journey of how to implement their
psyche ops how to change development and
how to make security parts of of the
change do you have any other interesting
projects are you currently working on
France fur there is no sir there was
really good one so Dennis Cruz and Seb
and myself decided to redo your Noah's
summit so we're building in North summit
global West summit so it was going to be
about seventy five a hundred
participants all the best people around
the planet
I seen you can be here
as well where we gonna work on lots of
working sessions so you've got threat
modeling you've got all different kind
of security facets projects that we
pinning together and it's basically a
non-conference five days sixty nowadays
working together and a sticking place in
June around London so if you're
interested go to or submit that org got
all the information information there
and we'll eye contact details to get
involved thanks for coming on today
France must know there has been lovely
and I see enough to commander and see
you in New Zealand awesome
Cheers excellent thank you very much Kim
[Music]
helped us make a sea radio even better
by completing our short listener survey
at WWI Tripoli org / SC radio thanks
thanks for listening the SC radio an
educational program brought to you by
Archer police software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website @ SC - radio
net to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack channel at SC
radio.com you can also email us at team
@ SC - radio net this and all other
episodes of SU radio is licensed under
Creative Commons license 2.5 thanks for
listening